[{"question": "What is an Array in C language.?", "option1": "A) A group of elements of same data type.", "option2": "\nB) An array contains more than one element\n", "option3": "\nC) Array elements are stored in memory in continuous or contiguous locations.\n", "option4": "\nD) All the above.\n", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C language arrays.", "option1": "A) An array address is the address of first element of array itself.", "option2": "\nB) An array size must be declared if not initialized immediately.\n", "option3": "\nC) Array size is the sum of sizes of all elements of the array.\n", "option4": "\nD) All the above\n", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "What are the Types of Arrays.?", "option1": "A) int, long, float, double", "option2": "\nB) struct, enum\n", "option3": "\nC) char\n", "option4": "\nD) All the above\n", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "An array Index starts with.?", "option1": "A) -1", "option2": "\nB) 0\n", "option3": "\nC) 1\n", "option4": "\nD) 2\n", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C language arrays.", "option1": "A) An array size can not changed once it is created.", "option2": "\nB) Array element value can be changed any number of times\n", "option3": "\nC) To access Nth element of an array students, use students[n-1] as the starting index is 0.\n", "option4": "\nD) All the above\n", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "What is the output of C Program.? int main() { int a[]; a[4] = {1,2,3,4}; printf(\"%d\", a[0]); }", "option1": "A) 1", "option2": "\nB) 2\n", "option3": "\nC) 4\n", "option4": "\nD) Compiler error\n", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "What is the output of C Program.? int main() { int a[] = {1,2,3,4}; int b[4] = {5,6,7,8}; printf(\"%d,%d\", a[0], b[0]); }", "option1": "A) 1,5", "option2": "\nB) 2,6\n", "option3": "\nC) 0 0\n", "option4": "\nD) Compiler error\n", "ans": "A"}, {"question": "What is the output of C Program.? int main() { char grade[] = {'A','B','C'}; printf(\"GRADE=%c, \", *grade); printf(\"GRADE=%d\", grade); }", "option1": "A) GRADE=some address of array, GRADE=A", "option2": "\nB) GRADE=A, GRADE=some address of array\n", "option3": "\nC) GRADE=A, GRADE=A\n", "option4": "\nD) Compiler error\n", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program.? int main() { char grade[] = {'A','B','C'}; printf(\"GRADE=%d, \", *grade); printf(\"GRADE=%d\", grade[0]); }", "option1": "A) A A", "option2": "\nB) 65 A\n", "option3": "\nC) 65 65\n", "option4": "\nD) None of the above\n", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program.? int main() { float marks[3] = {90.5, 92.5, 96.5}; int a=0; while(a<3) { printf(\"%.2f,\", marks[a]); a++; } }", "option1": "A) 90.5 92.5 96.5", "option2": "\nB) 90.50 92.50 96.50\n", "option3": "\nC) 0.00 0.00 0.00\n", "option4": "\nD) Compiler error\n", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the output of C Program.? int main() { int a[3] = {10,12,14}; a[1]=20; int i=0; while(i<3) { printf(\"%d \", a[i]); i++; } }", "option1": "A) 20 12 14", "option2": "\nB) 10 20 14\n", "option3": "\nC) 10 12 20\n", "option4": "\nD) Compiler error\n", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program.? int main() { int a[3] = {10,12,14}; int i=0; while(i<3) { printf(\"%d \", i[a]); i++; } }", "option1": "A) 14 12 10", "option2": "\nB) 10 10 10\n", "option3": "\nC) 10 12 14\n", "option4": "\nD) None of the above\n", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is the output of C Program.? int main() { int a[3] = {20,30,40}; a[0]++; int i=0; while(i<3) { printf(\"%d \", i[a]); i++; } }", "option1": "A) 20 30 40", "option2": "\nB) 41 30 20\n", "option3": "\nC) 21 30 40\n", "option4": "\nD) None of the above\n", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with arrays.? int main() { int a[3] = {20,30,40}; int b[3]; b=a; printf(\"%d\", b[0]); }", "option1": "A) 20", "option2": "\nB) 30\n", "option3": "\nC) address of 0th element.\n", "option4": "\nD) Compiler error\n", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is the output of C Program with arrays and pointers.? int main() { int a[3] = {20,30,40}; int (*p)[3]; p=&a; printf(\"%d\", (*p)[0]); }", "option1": "A) 20", "option2": "\nB) 0\n", "option3": "\nC) address of element 20\n", "option4": "\nD) Compiler error\n", "ans": "A"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with arrays and pointers.? int main() { int a[3] = {20,30,40}; int *p[3]; p=&a; printf(\"%d\", *p[0]); }", "option1": "A) 20", "option2": "\nB) address of element 20\n", "option3": "\nC) Garbage value\n", "option4": "\nD) Compiler error\n", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with arrays and pointers.? int main() { int a[3] = {20,30,40}; printf(\"%d\", *(a+1)); }", "option1": "A) 20", "option2": "\nB) 30\n", "option3": "\nC) 40\n", "option4": "\nD) Compiler error\n", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is an array Base Address in C language.?", "option1": "A) Base address is the address of 0th index element.", "option2": "\nB) An array b[] base address is &b[0]\n", "option3": "\nC) An array b[] base address can be printed with printf(\"%d\", b);\n", "option4": "\nD) All the above\n", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is the output of C Program with arrays and pointers.? void change(int[]); int main() { int a[3] = {20,30,40}; change(a); printf(\"%d %d\", *a, a[0]); } void change(int a[]) { a[0] = 10; }", "option1": "A) 20 20", "option2": "\nB) 10 20\n", "option3": "\nC) 10 10\n", "option4": "\nD) 20 30\n", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " An entire array is always passed by ___ to a called function.", "option1": "A) Call by value", "option2": "\nB) Call by reference\n", "option3": "\nC) Address relocation\n", "option4": "\nD) Address restructure\n", "ans": "B"}]
